welcome back we want to talk about
欢迎回来，我们要谈
progressive sanctification so if you
渐进的成圣，如果你
have your notes why don't you grab them
记下你为什么不抓住它们
and turn over to a little note page
并转到一个小笔记页面
there that says progressive
那里说进步
sanctification the biblical process of
圣化是圣经的圣经过程
change now during our last session Wayne
现在在我们上一届Wayne会议期间改变
Johnson talked quite a bit about the
约翰逊谈到了这个问题
problem of sin and he talked about harm
罪的问题，他谈到了伤害
our theology which is a theological term
我们的神学是一个神学术语
actually borrowed from the Greek term of
实际借用了希腊语
sin and and we want to talk a little bit
犯罪，我们要谈一点点
about that in relationship to progress
关于与进步的关系
the sanctification and move on from
成圣并继续前进
there and talk about it in broader view
在那里， 从更广泛的角度 谈论它
but let's take a look at the macro view
但是让我们来看看宏视图
of sin and the problem of sin and begin
罪和罪的问题，并开始
to divine define and interpret problems
神圣的定义和解释问题
the way the Bible interprets problems
圣经解释问题的方式
okay that means that we've got to set
好吧，这意味着我们必须设置
aside what we've been trained
除了我们接受过的培训
psychologically in the past and just
在过去和公正的心理上
look what theology says about the
看一下神学所说的
problem of sin and there is this macro
罪的问题， 有这个宏
view of sin and and how it affects a
罪的观点以及它如何影响一个人
person and how we worship every human
人和我们如何崇拜每一个人
heart on the planet was designed to
这个星球上的心被设计成
worship even the most adamant atheist
崇拜即使是最坚定的无神论者
even them the acknowledged agnostic has
即使他们是公认的不可知论者
a worshiping heart it's just that they
一个崇拜的心，就是他们
don't worship the God of heaven they
不要崇拜他们的天堂之神
worship themselves or they worship money
崇拜自己或崇拜金钱
or they worship things or people but
还是他们崇拜的事物或人，但
they every heart worships and the key
他们每个人都崇拜和关键
here is what it what is it that we
这就是我们的意义所在
worship when we're not worshiping the
当我们不崇拜时，敬拜
God of glory who created us then this is
创造我们的荣耀之神然后就是这样
a sinful heart and we have a sin problem
一个有罪的心，我们有一个罪恶的问题
we can see this from the very beginning
我们从一开始就能看到这一点
in Genesis chapter 3 there with Adam and
在创世记第3章中有亚当和
Eve God's curse upon sin man had divine
夏娃上帝对罪恶的诅咒是神圣的
counsel before the fall he was innocent
在堕落之前，他是无辜的
but not autonomous nor was he
但不是自主的，也不是他
independent in fact Adam even in his
事实上亚当甚至在他的身上
innocence before sin
在罪之前是无罪的
not rightly interpret the universe
不正确地解释宇宙
around him he needed God through
在他周围他需要通过上帝
revelation to interpret that and so God
启示来解释那个上帝
was able to reveal the atom this is what
能够揭示原子这是什么
you're supposed to do this is what
你应该这样做是什么
you're not supposed to do an atom now
你现在不应该做一个原子
then went about following the
然后继续关注
instructions of God
上帝的指示
you could eat of this but you cannot eat
你可以吃这个，但你不能吃
of this and so God now structures atoms
这一点，所以上帝现在构造原子
moral universe that's what he does he
道德宇宙那是他做什么，他
structure atoms moral universe with
结构原子道德宇宙与
right and wrong true/false and so from
对与错是真是假等等
the very beginning God created man to be
一开始上帝创造了人类
a counsel receiver because he
律师接待人，因为他
communicates his truth to him and he
向他和他传达他的真相
created man to be a counsel giver we can
创造人是一名律师送礼，我们可以
see this when the serpent comes and
当蛇来的时候看到这个
tests Eve and Eve argues with the
测试夏娃和夏娃的争论
serpent talks back to the serpent but
蛇会谈回蛇，但
then eventually falls prey to the wiles
然后最终成为诡计的牺牲品
of Satan at that particular point man as
撒旦在那个特定点上的人
well also as we also required the
因为我们也需要
counsel of the word in Genesis 3:8 and
在创世纪3字法律顾问 ：8
without the word now life is absurd life
没有这个词现在生活是荒谬的生活
has no purpose it has no future without
没有目的没有未来
the Word of God and Adam is the same way
上帝的话语和亚当​​是一样的
Adam has no future no purpose without
亚当是没有前途没有目的，没有
God and His Word and so this is why God
上帝和他的话语，所以这就是为什么上帝
now reveals himself to Adam so Adam at
现在向亚当展示自己，让亚当在
his very core had the capacity to be
他的核心有能力
able to understand language and receive
能够理解语言和接受
counsel from God and turn around and
从神律师和转身
form language and give counsel to other
形成语言并为其他人提供咨询
people even secular psychology
人甚至是世俗心理学
understands that because they talk about
理解，因为他们谈论
how our the brain of man has been formed
我们人类的大脑是如何形成的
only they are going to attribute it to
只有他们会把 它归因于
evolutionary theory where we're going to
我们要去的进化理论
retribute it to the creative act of God
将它归功于上帝的创造性行为
and each brain has a L
每个大脑都有一个L.
or language acquisition device and no
或语言习得设备，没有
matter how or where a person comes from
无论一个人来自何方何地
on this planet they all have the
在这个星球上他们都拥有
capacity to be able to understand
能够理解的能力
language and in some way communicate
语言，并以某种方式沟通
some of you probably read the story of
你们当中有些人可能会读到这个故事
Helen Keller for the longest time they
海伦凯勒他们的时间最长
thought the Helen Keller was a an idiot
以为海伦凯勒是个白痴
that she she was a buffoon but it wasn't
她是一个小丑， 但事实并非如此
until her nurse was able to develop a
直到她的护士能够发展出一个
language of communication with her
与她沟通的语言
through touch
通过触摸
did they finally realize that Helen
他们终于意识到了海伦
Keller was not an idiot she wasn't
凯勒不是一个她不是的白痴
stupid she wasn't a buffoon on the
傻，她 不是一个小丑在
contrary she was very very intelligent
相反， 她非常聪明
and even though she was a deaf blind
即使她是一个聋盲人
mute she had concepts of color where did
静音她有颜色哪儿来的概念
that come from
来自。 来自
she had concepts of the way people are
她有人们的概念
and and and personalities among people
和和人之间的人格
where did that come from as a deafblind
哪里是来自一个盲聋
mute
静音
Wow that that came from the God
哇那是来自上帝
instilled information and conscience
灌输信息和良心
that God had given her as a created
上帝把她作为创造者给了她
being and she could communicate she
存在，她可以与她沟通
wasn't an idiot even though she didn't
即使她没有 ，也不是白痴
communicate the same way you and I do
沟通你和我做 同样的方式
verbally she still had the capacity to
从口头上讲，她仍然有能力
communicate even though with her one
即使与她 交流也能沟通
sense of being able to touch then she
能接触她的感觉
could communicate in that way and and
这样，才能沟通，并
and learn and actually learn to read
并学习并实际学会阅读
through her sense of touch so we all
通过她的触觉让我们所有人
have the capacity to be able to
必须能够对容量
communicate God is the one who has given
沟通上帝是给予的人
that to us but you also know that back
这给我们，但你也知道，回
in Genesis chapter three man then turned
在创世纪第三章的人然后转过身来
from that divine Council to devilish
从那个神圣的委员会到恶魔
council and if you grab your Bible just
理事会，如果你只是抓住你的圣经
for a moment us go back to Genesis
我们回到创世纪
chapter three you can see this and the
第三章你可以看到这个和
development of this when sin now enters
当罪进入时，这种发展
into the created domain and verse one
到所创建的结构域和一个节
now the serpent was more crafty than any
现在蛇比任何人都更狡猾
beast of the field which the Lord God
主神的领域的野兽
had made and he said to the woman indeed
他做了，他确实对那个女人说
has God said you shall not eat from any
上帝说你不会吃任何东西
tree of the garden so what is serpent
花园的树， 所以什么是蛇
done here a serpent has sowed doubt and
在这里做了一条蛇已经播下了怀疑和
Eve's mind about this is this what
夏娃对此的想法是这样的
really God has said are are you sure
真的上帝说过你确定吗？
that's what God has said
这就是上帝所说的
so is doubt verse 2 the woman said to
因此怀疑女人所说的第2节
the serpent from the fruit of the trees
来自树木果实的蛇
of the garden we may eat she said
她说，我们可以吃 的花园
well in reality that's not exactly what
实际上，这并不完全是什么
God has said so already because of that
上帝也是这么说的已经因为这个
doubt she's beginning to distort exactly
怀疑她开始完全扭曲
what the words of God and the way that
什么是上帝的话语和那种方式
God had given his counsel to Adam and
上帝已经赐给亚当和他的忠告
Eve and then by time we get to verse 4
夏娃，然后我们到了第4节
then the serpent said to the woman you
然后那条蛇对那个女人说
surely will not die because verse 3 she
肯定不会因为第3节而死
says but from the fruit of the tree in
但是从树的果实说
which in the middle of the garden has
在 花园中间有
God said you shall not eat from it or
上帝说你不能吃它或
touch it he doesn't say that or you will
触摸它他不会说或你会
die and then the serpent just openly
只是公开地死了，然后是蛇
denies what God says you're not gonna
否认上帝说你不会
die you're not gonna die that's that's
你不会死的那就是那个
just wrong so now there is a denial of
错了，所以现在有一个否认
God's Word and then verse 5 for God
上帝的话语，然后是上帝的第5节
knows that in the day that you eat from
知道你吃的 那一天
it your eyes will be opened and you will
它你的眼睛会被打开，你会
be like God knowing good and evil so
就像上帝知道善恶一样
there then becomes a denunciation of God
然后在那里成为对上帝的谴责
so at that particular point Eve now has
所以在那个特殊的时刻，伊娃现在已经有
ceased being a helper now she has become
现在她已成为一名助手
a Harmar and there's two main lies here
哈马尔，这里有两个主要的谎言
that Satan once Eve to believe 1 that
撒旦一旦夏娃相信那1
God wants to keep you in bondage in your
上帝希望让你处于束缚之中
ignorance
无知
that's it nobody wants to be in bondage
那就是没有人想要受到束缚
or in live from a standpoint of
或从生活的角度来看
ignorance and the second big lie is
无知和第二大谎言是
there is no judgment God will not bring
没有上帝不会带来的判断
judgment
判断
that's not true either in fact there's a
这是不正确或者在事实上有一个
terrible judgment to follow and of
可靠的判断跟随和
course you know the story we don't have
当然，你知道，我们没有故事
to belabor the point that man rejected
belabor是男人拒绝的观点
divine counsel and suffered the
神圣的忠告并遭受了
consequences from for it there is
从它出现 的后果
twofold consequences there was immediate
立即产生双重后果
consequences that occurred in Adam and
亚当和亚当发生的后果
Eve's life where they gain knowledge of
夏娃的一生中，他们获得的知识
good and evil but they lost the power to
善恶，但他们失去了力量
affect change they gain guilt and
影响改变他们有罪并且
separation and blindness and rejecting
分离，失明和拒绝
responsibility and developed problems
责任和发达的问题
with God and others and self and then
与上帝和他人以及自我然后
there are eternal consequences which was
有永恒的后果
spiritual death and then later physical
精神死亡再后来身体
and eternal death now was experienced as
和永恒的死亡，现在是有经验的
Romans 5:12 says the sin of Adam plunged
罗马书5:12说亚当的罪恶暴跌
the entire human race you and I into sin
整个人类你和我陷入罪恶
there there's the situation that's the
那里的情况就是这样的
world in which we live we're affected in
我们生活的世界我们受到了影响
it in our spirit soul immaterial part of
它在我们的精神灵魂无形的一部分
man we're affected in the material part
我们在材料部分受到影响
of man there are elements of death in
男人中有死亡的元素
every one of our bodies there's that's
我们每个人的身体都是那样的
the encouraging words you can take home
鼓励的话，你可以带回家
tonight all right all right if it were
今晚没关系，如果是的话
not for your immune system there are
不是为了你的免疫系统
things already in your body that would
事情已经在你的身体那会
attack it and kill it right now so we
攻击它并立即杀死它，所以我们
live in an environment like that we have
住在 那样我们有一个环境
a professor there at the Masters College
马斯特学院的教授
who his specialty is microbiology and he
他的专长是微生物学和他
gives great lectures I love love to
给我喜爱的精彩讲座
listen to him on microbiology prior to
在听之前听他讲微生物学
the fall and how bacteria that's harmful
秋天和细菌是如何有害的
bacteria you know we we carpet-bomb
细菌你知道我们是地毯炸弹
bacteria but most bacteria in the world
细菌，但世界上大多数细菌
is really really good bacteria bacteria
真的是真的好细菌
prior to the fall was all good it was a
在秋天之前，这一切都很好
hundred percent good nothing harmful
百分之百好无害
after the fall had only changed about 3%
跌倒后只变了3％左右
of the bacteria the rest of it ninety
细菌它的其余部分90
seven percent of it is still very very
百分之七仍然非常非常
good bacteria
好细菌
and bacteria all over the place but we
我们到处都是细菌
carpet-bomb bacteria with 100%
地毯炸弹细菌100％
antiseptic things so we're killing all
防腐的东西，所以我们杀了所有
this good stuff and in order to get rid
这个好东西，为了摆脱
of the bad so but after the fall only
这是坏事，但仅在跌倒后
only a minor changes in bacteria now
现在细菌只有微小的变化
brings about death just minor little
导致死亡只是轻微的一点点
changes we live in that world it's
我们生活在那个世界的变化
cursed
诅咒
it's cursed we have bacteria that will
它被诅咒我们有细菌会
kill us
杀了我们
scary and we can see the continuation of
可怕，我们可以看到延续
that then later on when the Bible talks
然后在圣经谈话时
about the fact that we can see it with
关于我们可以看到它的事实
the first man who's born Cain Cain's
谁是天生该隐该隐的 第一个男人
anger and jealousy now is manifested as
愤怒和嫉妒现在表现为
a result of sin towards her his brother
罪恶对她的兄弟的结果
Abel and it's interesting Abel's the
亚伯和它们也同样吸引阿贝尔的
Hebrew word for Abel is of all which you
阿贝尔的希伯来语就是你的一切
can hear the English come through a
能听到英语来自
table of all it's the same word that's
所有这一切都是同一个词
used in the book of ecclesiastes of all
在所有的教会书中使用
Havoline vanity of vanities all is
虚空的虚空金富力全是
vanity or smoke smoke everything smoke
虚荣或烟雾吸烟一切烟雾
that was Abel's name Abel's name later
这是亚伯的名字后来的亚伯的名字
on became the name for meaningless
on成了毫无意义的名字
meaningless everything's meaningless or
毫无意义的一切都是毫无意义的
sometimes when I teach Ecclesiastes so
有时当我教导传道书时
bubbles so bubbles
气泡如此泡沫
everything in this world's like so
这个世界上的一切都是这样的
bubbles it's there for a short amount of
泡泡它的数量很少
time and and then it's gone it's a
时间，然后它就消失了
Valhalla lien it's Abel Abel that was
瓦尔哈拉留置权是亚伯亚伯这是
Abel's life it was like a smoke that was
亚伯的生活，那简直就像烟雾，这是
there for a short amount of time and
那里的时间很短
that was gone
那已经过去了
Abel became an analogy for everything
亚伯成了一切的类比
that was meaningless because of sin
因罪而无意义
everything's reduced to meaninglessness
一切都变成了无意义
of all Halim meaningless meaningless
所有哈利姆都毫无意义
it's all meaningless we can see that we
我们可以看到我们都毫无意义
can see it in the first king of Israel
可以在以色列的第一位国王看到它
he's hidden Saul's life for Samuel 13
他为撒母耳13隐藏了扫罗的生命
all the way through 31 his struggles
他一直在努力奋斗
eventually his suspicions about David
最终他对大卫的怀疑
here David was incredibly 100% devoted
在这里大卫非常忠诚于100％
to King Saul and yet King Saul was
扫罗王，但扫罗王是
jealous over the fact that the women of
嫉妒在事实的女人
Israel are going around saying that
以色列被绕来绕去说
David Saul had killed his thousands but
大卫扫罗杀了他的数千人但是
david had killed us ten thousand
大卫杀了我们一万
and David wasn't even King how could
大卫甚至不是国王怎么可能
these women talk about him being greater
这些女人谈论他更伟大
and jealousy turned into hatred hatred
和嫉妒变成仇恨仇恨
to a plot to kill David you can see that
一个杀死大卫的阴谋，你可以看到
sin pressing forward and then of course
罪恶向前，然后当然
Romans chapter 3 verses 9 through 23 is
罗马书3章9到23节是
that classic passage where Paul the
保罗的经典通道
Apostle Paul's assessment of all mankind
使徒保罗对全人类的评价
at the time of Paul we've we've all
保罗的时候我们都是
sinned we've all fallen short of the
得罪我们都达不到的
glory of God there's none righteous no
上帝的荣耀没有正义的没有
not one none and then we can see its
没有一个没有，然后我们可以看到它
present reality even today grab your
目前的现实， 即使今天抢你的
Bible let's go over to 2nd Timothy
圣经让我们回到第二提摩太
chapter 3 present reality today and this
第3章介绍了现实和现实
is really fascinating because if you
真是令人着迷，因为如果你
study the Bible for very long and study
长期研读 圣经并研究
the structure of the way the semantic
语义的结构方式
months Medic mind works you know that
几个月医学思想工作，你知道
when oftentimes Semitic mine wanted to
当闪电矿经常想要的时候
list a whole list of things it put the
列出一整套放入的东西
broadest thing at the top that kind of
最顶层的那种东西
characterized everything underneath it
描述了它下面的一切
and you can see this in 2nd Timothy 3
你可以在提摩太后书3中看到这一点
that's what's really going on he says in
这到底发生了什么对他说：
verse 1 but realize this that in last
第1节， 但最后意识到这一点
days difficult times will come in fact
实际上，困难时期将到来
the Greek word for difficult is the word
希腊语中的难点就是这个词
that we oftentimes are translate
我们经常翻译
dangerous dangerous times will come in
危险的危险时刻将进来
the last days and then he gives a whole
最后几天，然后他给了一个整体
list of what they're going to be like
他们将会是什么样的清单
and it's interesting what's at the very
而且非常有趣
top of this list for men will be what
这个男人名单的首位将是什么
lovers of self now I was taught when I
现在我和自己的爱好者被教导了
went through college that's a virtue
经历了大学，这是一种美德
Paul calls it a vice it's what's going
保罗称之为副作品，它正在发生什么
to make the last days dangerous men will
让最后几天危险的男人会
be self lovers and then it says because
是自恋者然后它说因为
their self lovers they'll love money
他们的自爱人他们会爱钱
because their self lovers they'll be
因为他们是自己的爱人
boastful because their self lovers
自夸是因为他们的自恋者
they'll be arrogant because their self
他们因为自己而傲慢自大
lovers they'll be revilers because those
恋人，因为那些，他们将成为叛徒
self lovers they'll be disobedient to
自恋人，他们会不听话
parent
亲
and all the parents can say Amen because
所有的父母都可以说阿门因为
their self lovers they'll be ungrateful
他们的自恋者他们会忘恩负义
because their self lovers they'll be
因为他们的自我的恋人，他们会
unholy because their self lovers they'll
不圣洁， 因为他们的自爱他们会
be unloving to others irreconcilable
对别人不可调和的不爱
bullish malicious gossips without
没有看涨的恶意流言蜚语
self-control brutal haters of good
善于控制野蛮的仇恨
treacherous reckless conceited lovers of
奸诈的鲁莽自负的恋人
pleasure rather than lovers of God
快乐而不是上帝的爱人
holding to a form of godliness although
保持到敬虔虽然形式
they have denied its power avoid such
他们否认其权力避免了这种情况
men as these not only have we not
这些人不仅没有我们
avoided them we've welcomed those kind
避免他们我们欢迎那些
of people into our churches that teach
人们进入我们教导的教会
us how to love ourselves even more
我们如何更爱自己
that's horrible
那太糟了
do you know nowhere in the Bible not one
你知道圣经中没有一个人没有
single verse in the Bible does that ever
圣经中的单节经文就是这样
say we need to love ourselves more but
说我们需要更多地爱自己
the Bible is literally full of
圣经充满了
admonitions to be careful because we
告诫要小心，因为我们
often love ourselves too much that's
经常爱自己太多这
where we get ourselves into trouble boy
我们陷入困境的男孩
what does that do to personality and
这对个性和人格有什么影响？
self esteem and psychology what does
什么是自尊和心理学
that do to it Alfred Adler you know now
你现在知道阿尔弗雷德阿德勒
for Adler believed Adler believed that
阿德勒相信阿德勒认为
by the time a person got to the age of
当一个人到了这个年龄的时候
six
六
by that time since everybody was bigger
到那个时候， 因为每个人都更大
stronger smarter than they were that
比他们更聪明
stamped on that person's psyche that
盖上那个人的心灵
child's psyche is an inferiority complex
孩子的心灵是一种自卑情结
that he spends the rest of his life
他度过余生
trying to compensate for he tries to
试图弥补他的努力
seek whatever Adler used to call
寻求阿德勒过去常常打电话
superiority that is he was trying to
优势就是他 试图
compensate for that infuriated complex
弥补这一愤怒的复杂
but that word superiority became too
但是这个词的优势也变得如此
pejorative and later on and learn had to
贬义，后来学习不得不
change it to self-realization man every
每次 都把它变成自我实现的人
person in order to compensate for their
为了弥补他们的人
inferiority complex is trying to get to
自卑情结正在努力实现
a level where their self realized is the
他们自我意识到的水平
idea well all of that gives impetus to
想法好了这一切带动了
the self love self-esteem movement
自爱自尊运动
that's part of this world that's all of
这就是这个世界的一部分
it but
它但是
according to scriptures that's the very
根据经文，这是非常的
core of sin that's the very core said
罪恶的核心是核心所说的
the fact that we love self intently I'll
事实上，我们会非常热爱自己
never forget a few years ago I was
几年前我从未忘记
sitting in my office and one of my
坐在我的办公室和我的一个
students came to the door she was a very
学生找上门来了，她是一个非常
bright student
聪明的学生
she kind of pecked on the door it was
她有点啄门了
kind of cracked open she's a doctor
有点破开她是医生
Street you got a moment and I looked at
街上你有片刻我看了看
the pile of work and I looked at her I
一堆工作，我看着她
looked the pile of work I said sure come
看着那堆我确实来的工作
in so she came in sat down she looked at
在让她进来坐了下来，她看着
the floor had that puppy-dog look you
地板上有那只小狗看着你
know really saggy face I said what's
知道真的下垂的脸我说的是什么
wrong she said I hate myself you do yep
错了， 她说我讨厌自己，你做的是
well are you miserable depressed hate
好吧，你是痛苦的沮丧恨
myself oh now I know never to ask this
我自己哦，现在我知道永远不要问这个
question but I'd do it anyhow why do you
问题，但无论如何我都会这样做
hate yourself because you're gonna get a
恨你自己， 因为你会得到一个
whole litany of stuff and you got to be
一连串的东西，你必须
prepared for a whole hour lecture all
整整一个小时的演讲准备的所有
right I'm too tall too short too fat too
对，我太高太短太胖了
skinny
枯瘦
I have the wrong color complexion got
我有错色的肤色有
big ears crooked nose people don't like
大耳朵弯曲的鼻子让人不喜欢
me I'm not attractive enough and so I
我， 我不够吸引力，所以我
listened to this for the next half hour
在接下来的半小时里听了这个
just went on and on why she hated
只是继续，为什么她讨厌
herself when she got done she said what
她完成后她说了什么
do you think
你觉得吗？
they should learn not to ask that of me
他们应该学会不要问我
I said you know what I'm really really
我说你知道我真的是什么
confused now she was a very smart
困惑现在她很聪明
student she says why you confused so
她说学生为什么这么困惑
well you came in and you said you hated
嗯，你进来，你说你讨厌
yourself yeah and then you told me you
亲爱的，然后你告诉我你
were miserable right hmm you told me you
相当难受右嗯，你告诉我你
were depressed yep
精神抑郁是的
well it doesn't make any sense to me
好吧，这对我没有任何意义
well why doesn't it make any sense well
以及为何它没有任何意义以及
think about it I mean if you really
想想我的意思是，如果你真的
hated self that were really true you
恨自己，是真的你
would be happy you're a weirdo that
会很高兴你是一个古怪的人
you're too tall too short to have too
你太高太矮了也不能拥有
fat too skinny
胖太瘦了
you got a crooked nose big ears wrong
你有一个弯曲的鼻子大耳朵错了
complexion you're not academic enough
肤色你不够学习
you're not athletic enough you'd be
你运动能力不够好
happy she set there and
高兴她就坐下来，
I said you know what
我说你知道的
nowhere in the Bible's that ever say we
圣经中的那个曾经说过，我们
hate ourselves in fact we love ourselves
实际上我们恨自己，我们爱自己
a lot now it doesn't mean we don't hate
现在很多并不意味着我们不讨厌
certain things about ourselves but the
关于自己，但某些事情
very fact that we're miserable shows
事实上，我们是悲惨的节目
that we love ourselves intently you
我们热爱你自己
follow me so I took her to several
跟我来， 所以我把她带到了几个
scriptures especially in Matthew 22
经文特别是在马太福音22章
where Jesus said she he answers the
耶稣说她回答了这个问题
disciples and he talks about the fact
门徒和他谈论这个事实
you show love Lord your God with all
你向所有人显示爱你的上帝
your heart soul mind and strength and
你心灵的灵魂和力量
love your neighbor as yourself
爱你的邻居就像你自己
oh yeah she says there you're supposed
哦，是的，她说那里你应该
to love yourself that's not what Jesus
要爱自己，那不是耶稣
is saying in fact the very next verse it
实际上是在说下一节经文
says upon these two commands the whole
说完这两个命令
law hangs not three not loving God
法律不是三个不爱上帝
loving others loving self he says two
爱他人爱自己他说两句
commands loving God loving others well
爱神爱他人的命令
what does he mean love others as
他的意思是爱他人
yourself he means love others as
他自己意味着爱别人
passionately as you already love
热情地如你所爱
yourself
你自己
he actually assumes you love yourself
他实际上假设你爱自己
way too much really
实在太多了
and you know what in tears she repented
你知道她悔改了什么
of that next hour I saw her in the
那个下一个小时我看到了她
cafeteria and I'm sitting across the
食堂，我坐在他对面的
cafeteria watching her go through the
看着她的自助餐厅经历了
salad line and she picks up the tongs in
色拉线和她拿起在钳
the salad line and she comes through
沙拉线，她来了
this great big bowl of red cherry
这大碗红樱桃
tomatoes and I'm sitting there watching
西红柿，我正坐在那儿看着
her and she picks up one cherry tomato
她和她拿起一个樱桃番茄
and she looks at it puts it back picks
她看着它把它放回去
up another one looks at it puts it back
另一个看着它把它放回去
picks up another one puts that on her
拿起另一个把它放在她身上
salad she's going through this
沙拉她正在经历这个
meticulous everybody's waiting on her
每个人都在等着她一丝不苟
behind and I'm saying to myself now what
后面，我现在对自己说什么
is she doing I know she hates herself so
她在做什么我知道她如此讨厌自己
she's looking for the worst tomatoes in
她正在寻找最糟糕的西红柿
the bunch no that's not what she was
这帮没有，这不是她是什么
doing she was looking for the best
她正在寻找最好的
tomatoes in the bunch why because she
西红柿在一堆为什么因为她
loves herself intently that's our
我热爱自己就是我们的
default nature and that's the very thing
默认的性质，这就是事情
that makes the last days terrible why do
这使得最后几天可怕的原因
you do what you do why do you yell at
你做你做的事你为什么大喊大叫
your wife because you love yourself why
你的妻子，因为你爱自己为什么
do you get so intently angry at your
你是如此专注于你的生气吗？
husband because you love yourself why do
老公， 因为你爱自己为什么呢
you think I can't put up with these kids
你认为我不能忍受这些孩子
one more day because you love yourself
还有一天，因为你爱自己
that's why that's what makes the last
这就是为什么这是最后的原因
days dangerous
天危险
so the Bible's very realistic in the
所以圣经在这方面很现实
last days there's going to be wholesale
最后几天会有批发
iniquity and hypocrisy there's gonna be
那将是罪恶和虚伪
wholesale apostasy there's going to be
批评叛教会有
wholesale persecution for those that are
对那些人的批发迫害
really committed to doing things God's
真的致力于做上帝的事
Way
办法
so the alternatives is well you can quit
所以你可以放弃替代品
and many 1/2 or you can seek help from
许多1/2或者您也可以寻求帮助
man's counsel to deal with these
男人的律师处理这些问题
problems there are many who go that
问题有很多谁去那
route - or you can seek help from the
路线- 或者你可以寻求帮助
Word of God as second timothy 3:15
神的话语作为第二蒂莫西3:15
through 4 - says there's the world in
通过4  - 说有世界
which we live and there's the curse of
我们生活在哪里，有诅咒
sin that's what's going on now if we
如果我们这就是现在正在发生的事
were to take a micro view of this and I
是对我和我的微观看法
wish I had more time to spend on this
希望我有更多的时间花在这上面
but I don't the issue is the heart of
但我不是问题的核心
man there's the problem and Genesis
男人有问题和创世纪
chapter 6 and verse 5 if you want to
如果你愿意，可以参考第6章和第5节
grab your Bible again let's go back
再次抓住你的圣经让我们回去吧
there just for a moment we're not going
那里只是一会儿我们不打算
to be able to look at every single verse
要能够 看到每一个节
here that we have listed but you can do
在这里，我们已经列出但你可以做到
that on your own study Genesis chapter 6
在你自己的研究创世纪第6章
and verse 5 then the Lord saw and the
然后耶和华见了第5节
Hebrew here is he continually saw it's
希伯来语在这里是他不断看到的
not that he just saw it one time he
不是说他只是一次见到它
continually saw that the wickedness of
不断地看到了邪恶
man was great on the earth and that
那个人 在地球上很棒
every intent of the thoughts of his
他的思想的每一个意图
heart was only evil continually notice
心脏只是邪恶不断注意到
the way the heart is described it says
它描述了心脏的描述方式
the thoughts of the heart
心灵的想法
notice that the thoughts of the heart
注意到心灵的想法
was only evil continually
只是邪恶不断
there's the depravity of man thoughts of
还有 的人思想 的堕落
the heart Jesus talks about that in
有关的心脏耶稣会谈
Matthew 22 that I just mentioned verses
马太福音22章，我刚才提到的经文
33 34 through 40 or grab your Bible
33 34到40或抓住你的圣经
again let's go over to proverbs chapter
让我们回到谚语章节
4 and verse 23 proverbs 4:23 here
4和23节箴言4:23在这里
Solomon just before he goes into a
所罗门就在他进入之前
lengthy three chapter session on sexual
关于性的冗长的三章会议
lust and temptation and adultery and
欲望和诱惑，通奸和
immorality
放荡
starts it by saying watch over your
通过说守你的方式来启动它
heart
心
now when you study proverbs you realize
现在，当你研究谚语时，你会意识到
the Hebrew word for heart is you can
希伯来语中的一句话就是你能做到的
substitute the word thinking or mind in
用思想或思想来代替
it and you're very close to what the
它和你很接近了什么
Hebrew concept ears watch over your
希伯来概念耳朵监视你的
thinking your mind with all diligence
与所有的努力想着你的心
for from it flows the springs of life in
用于从它流生活中的弹簧
other words everything else in life
换句话说生活中的其他一切
issues forth from there and you can see
从那里发出的问题，你可以看到
what Jesus says about that in mark
耶稣说，大约在 标记
chapter 7 if we had more time for Samuel
第7章如果我们有更多的时间为塞缪尔
16 Psalm 111 1 so the problem here has
16诗篇111 1所以问题就在于此
to do with the sin that is so self
处理那么自我的罪
focused that is full so full of
专注于满满的
self-love that we can't function or even
自爱，我们不能发挥作用，甚至
think correctly without thinking about
没有考虑就正确思考
how is this going to serve me better how
这是怎么回事，以更好地服务于我如何
is this going to serve me better that's
这会更好地为我服务吗？
so critical so if we were to look at it
如此重要，如果我们要看它
like this and put it kind of in a graph
像这样，把它放在一个图表中
form the heart now becomes the very
形成心脏现在变得非常
control center of man's life how he
控制中心男人的生活怎么样
thinks about his life now I know that we
现在想起他的生活，我知道我们
live in a merican European culture where
生活在美国的欧洲文化中
the heart is primarily related to
心脏主要与...有关
romantic and emotions I mean on
我的意思是浪漫和情感
Valentine's Day what do you see you see
情人节你看到了什么？
cards with hearts and him and Cupid and
卡与心和他和丘比特和
everything like that see it all over the
像一切看到这一切在
place but actually the Bible has a
但实际上圣经有一个
different organ of the Bible when it
圣经的不同器官当它
reorg another body that it refers to
REORG另一个机构，它是指
when it talks about emotions and that is
当谈到感情，这是
the bowels the bowels of the body that's
排便的是身体的大便
emotions all right
情绪没事
Ephesians 4:32 talks about the fact we
以弗所书有关的事实4:32 我们会谈
have to be tinder bow that's literally
必须是字面上的火种弓
what the Greek says that's when it's
希腊人说什么时候就是这样
talking about emotions anybody's been
谈论任何人的情绪
constipated for a long period of time
便秘很长一段时间
knows how emotional that is
知道这是多么的情绪化
so gentlemen if you really want to be
如此绅士，如果你真的想成为
biblical next valentine's day you're
圣经的下一个情人节你是
gonna say I love you with all my bowels
要说我全身心地爱你
now you're gonna be biblical we need
现在你将成为我们需要的圣经
whole new set of Christian greeting
全新的基督徒问候
cards that have vowels on them all right
这对他们没事元音卡
then we be biblical I'm not sure she'll
那么我们是圣经的我不确定她会不会
take it really well but so the heart
把它拿得很好，但内心却如此
though from a biblical standpoint has to
虽然从圣经的角度来看必须如此
do with thoughts it will conscience
做思想它将良知
motives desires all those things are
动机渴望所有这些事情
what the heart does in us see and when
我们心中所看到的是什么以及什么时候
the Bible talks about the outer man in
圣经谈到了外面的人
the inner man it's the inner man it's
内在的人它的内在的人是
the heart that God sees and from that
上帝所看到的心灵
heart comes all our behavior and either
心灵来自我们所有的行为
our our heart is right or it's it's
我们的心是对的还是它的
wrong when it's wrong the hearts focus
当心脏集中注意力时，错了
is going to be on self and then it's
将是自我，然后是
going to produce bad fruit in terms of
要坏果子来讲
behavior when it's right it's going to
当它的行为正确的它会
be focused on Christ and then it's going
集中于基督，然后它会
to produce good fruit in terms of
产生好的水果方面
behavior external behavior but it all
行为外部行为，但一切
goes back to the heart and it's what the
回到心脏，这是什么
heart does that is the key here that's
这是关键所在
the critical idea what is the heart do
关键的想法是什么是心脏
well I mentioned it a little bit earlier
好吧，我之前提到过它
you find out in Scripture that the heart
你在圣经中找到了那颗心
actually its occupation is one of
实际上它的职业是其中之一
worship in worships that's what the
崇拜中的崇拜就是这样的
heart does and you can see there are
心脏，你可以看到有
several passages even listed in your
几个段落甚至列在你的
notes then you can look up later on
注意，然后您可以稍后查找
Exodus chapter 20 in Romans 1 and
出埃及记第20章罗马书1和
Jeremiah 2 in first Kings 18 Matthew 12
耶利米书2在第一位国王18马太福音12章
Joshua 24 Romans 6 and Matthew chapter 6
约书亚24罗马书6章和马太福音6章
as well and so the heart worships it can
以及所以心灵崇拜它可以
worship a lot of things you got to
崇拜你所要做的很多事情
understand I'm a preacher so everything
明白我是传教士所以一切
has to be alliterated
必须是头衔
all right popularity piece play prestige
没事普及一块玩信誉
power pleasure people protection
权力乐趣人保护
physical health and possessions is that
身体健康和财产就是这样
good the heart worships that's what your
善良的心灵崇拜那是你的
heart does it worships it has something
心脏它崇拜它有什么
that it wants deep inside it has certain
它需要内心深处确定
desires that it wants more than anything
希望它比任何东西 都要多
else and they may start off of very
否则他们可能会开始
legitimate desires but then it can turn
合法的欲望， 但它可以转向
to wicked wicked desires in a nanosecond
在一纳秒内邪恶的邪恶欲望
and that's the frustration because the
这是令人沮丧的，因为
real issue here has to do with idolatry
这里真正的问题与偶像崇拜有关
and lust because when the heart then
和欲望，因为当心脏
begins to lust even for what starts off
甚至开始时也开始欲望
as a very little legitimate desire when
作为一个非常小的合法愿望
that happens then it becomes a sinful
那会发生，那就变成了罪恶
desire or a controlling and ruling
欲望或控制和裁决
desire in a heart and that's when the
心中的欲望，那就是
Bible talks about idolatry of the heart
圣经谈到了内心的偶像崇拜
anything that's worthwhile can become an
任何值得的东西都可以成为一个
idolatrous worship in your heart the
在你的心脏偶像崇拜的
heart of the person you're counseling
你咨询的人的心脏
what is that
那是什么
well that is wanting or desiring
那是想要还是想要的
something that God does not want or
上帝不想要的东西或
desire or wanting something that God
渴望或想要上帝的东西
wants or desires but wanting it so much
希望和愿望，但希望它这么多
that one becomes ungodly to get it or
得到它或那个人变得不敬虔
ungodly if you don't get it it's the
不敬虔的，如果你没有得到它就是
it's the wife who says and counseling to
这是妻子说和咨询
you you know all I want is for my
你知道我想要的就是我的
husband to love me that's all I want
丈夫爱我，这就是我想要的
or
要么
the husband who says in counseling to
在咨询中说的丈夫
you all I want is for my wife to respect
你想要的就是让我的妻子尊重
me that's all I want is that wrong no
我就是我想要的就是错误的不
either neither of those are wrong can
或者这些都不对
they become wrong oh yes in a nanosecond
他们在一个纳秒内变得错误哦是的
say how how does that happen because I
说这是怎么发生的，因为我
can want it so bad that it consumes me
可以想要它如此糟糕以至于消耗了我
it's the first thing I think about when
这是我想 的时候 第一件事情
I get up in the morning it's the last
我早上起床，这是最后一次
thing I think about before I go to bed
事情我想之前我去睡觉
at night and it's the thing that I dwell
在晚上，这 是我住 的东西
on all day long it consumes my thought I
一整天都消耗了我的想法
want that more than I want to be God's
我想要的不仅仅是我想成为上帝的
kind of woman or God's kind of man when
当某种女人或上帝的那种男人
those things consume me then my heart is
那些东西消耗了我然后我的心
worshiping an idol and Idol that now
现在崇拜偶像和偶像
wants to rule my life and it's
想要统治我的生活，这是
interesting to hear people talk about
听到人们谈论有趣
felt needs oh I have this felt need for
觉得需要哦我觉得需要
my husband to really pay attention to me
老公要真的好好关注我
felt needs biblically are deceptive
觉得需要圣经是欺骗性的
slave masters did you hear that felt
从属大师你听到了吗？
needs are deceptive slave masters in
需要是欺骗性的奴隶主
other words we become enslaved by that
换句话说，我们被这种奴役所束缚
felt need I need for my wife to follow
觉得我需要我的妻子跟随
my instructions
我的指示
really so I become consumed with that
真的让我厌倦了
getting her to follow my instructions
让她遵循我的指示
wanting something that God wants her
想要上帝想要她的东西
desires but wanting it so much that it
渴望但又想要它
become that I become ungodly to get it
成为我变得不敬虔得到它
or ungodly if I don't get it or being
或不敬虔的，如果我没有得到它或正在
controlled by expectations and becoming
受期望和成为控制
ungodly and fadh word or deed when the
不敬虔和愚蠢的言行
expectation somehow is not realized I
期待某种方式没有实现我
have an expectation that things are
期待事情的发展
going to turn out mmm and it doesn't
结果是mmm，但事实并非如此
turn out the way I expect but I wanted
转向我期望的方式，但我想要
to and it consumes me and in fact it
并且它消耗我，事实上它
controls my whole moods and I'm
控制我的整个情绪，我
depressed or I'm angry or I'm upset or
郁闷，或者我很生气，或者我很沮丧
I'm full of anxiousness or I'm full of
我充满了焦虑，或者我充满了
fears it's like the woman and her
担心这就像女人和她
husband several years ago that came in
丈夫几年前那排在
to me for counseling they were having
给我咨询他们的
some severe serious married marital
一些严重的严重婚姻婚姻
problems and and it centered around her
问题，并 以它为中心
little girls marpe I found out that her
小女孩马克我发现她
past background was that when she was a
过去的背景是，当她是一个
little girl about seven years old a man
七岁的小女孩一个男人
in a van pulled up in front of her house
一辆面包车在她家门前 拉起
kidnapped her horribly raped her as a
绑架她的可怕的强奸她作为一个
little girl she was able to escape they
小女孩，她能够逃脱他们
found out later that he had killed other
后来发现他杀死了 其他
little girls and so I said to her do you
小女孩，所以我跟她说你呢
believe your husband loves you oh yes
相信你的丈夫爱你哦，是的
absolutely
绝对
do you believe that he loves your little
你相信他爱你的小孩吗？
girls yes I do
女孩我是
but I can't let those girls out of my
但我不能让那些女孩离开我的
sight she talked about going down the
看到她说下去了
pier at Santa Monica
在圣塔莫尼卡码头
and there's merry-go-round there and she
那里有旋转木马和她
said my husband and my daughters would
我丈夫和女儿说
get on the mirror ground and they it
得到上镜地面和他们IT
would start to go around and when they
他们会开始四处奔走
disappear out of sight I'd go into
消失看不见我走进
full-blown panic attack until they came
全面的惊恐发作直到他们来了
back around and then disappear go into
回来然后消失进去
full-blown panic attack took him back
全面的惊恐发作把他带回来
came back around panic attack
惊恐发作时回来了
she said I I just can't let him out of
她说，刚II 不能让他出去的
my sight I said you know if you continue
我的视线我告诉你，如果你继续
this year your little girls that are
今年你的小女孩是
grow up to teenagers and they're gonna
成长为青少年，他们会
despise you and hate you because you're
鄙视你， 恨你，因为你
gonna be so controlling in their life
会如此控制他们的生活
you can lock them away in their room for
你可以将它们锁在自己的房间里
the next 20 years and a meteor could
未来 20年，流星可能
fall out of the sky and crush them oh I
从天而降，粉碎他们哦
didn't think about that gave her a new
没有想到这给了她一个新的
fear I said you know you know what I'm
害怕我说你知道你知道我是什么
getting at here this has become an
到达这里已成为一个
obsession in your life I have to protect
在你的生活中迷恋 我必须保护
them no you don't you don't have to you
他们不，你不你没有你
can trust the Lord with them this is an
可以信靠主与他们这是一个
idolatrous desire and expectation that
拜偶像的欲望和期望
you have set up in your heart and it's
你已经在心里建立起来了
going to destroy your marriage and it
要破坏你的婚姻吧
will eventually destroy your
最终将摧毁你的
relationship to your own daughters being
与你自己的女儿的关系
controlled by things there are things
由事物控制有事物
that control you that maybe don't affect
控制你可能不会影响你
other people but they affect you
其他人，但他们影响你
perceiving it deserved right and
感知它应得的权利，
following through with ungodly thoughts
跟着不敬虔的想法
words and actions to try to get it when
试图在何时获得它的单词和行动
that right is denied you can probably
你可能会拒绝这项权利
think of his instances in your own life
想想他在你自己生活中的实例
where that's the case I've got to have
在那种情况下，我必须拥有
that and I'm willing to lie cheat steal
那个，我愿意骗骗骗子
misuse somebody else in order to get
为了获得而 误用别人
something that I want more than anything
我想要的东西比什么都重要
else or believing in something a
其他或东西相信
standard or a rule that is not of God
标准或不属于上帝的规则
that leads to ungodly practices what is
导致不敬虔的做法是什么
your heart worship my ruling desires my
你的心崇拜我的执政欲望
functional God's controlling
功能上帝的控制
intergrating x' are my idolatrous
整合x'是我偶像崇拜
desires thinking having a mindset that
渴望思考有一种心态
is
是
against the truth of God's Word and that
对神的话语和真理
leads to ungodliness in thoughts words
在思想词汇中导致不敬虔
and actions when your heart begins to
和操作时 ， 你的心脏开始
say I must have that or I must not have
说我必须拥有，或者我必须拥有
that then your heart has become
然后你的心就变成了
idolatrous I must have that promotion I
崇拜偶像，我必须有 我的推广
must have that respect from so-and-so I
必须从某某所以这方面我
must have that love from so-and-so I
必须从某某让我的爱
must have that car I must have that
我必须拥有那辆车
house I must have a bank account that is
家，我必须有一个银行帐户，也就是
X number of zeros behind it maybe it all
它背后的 X个零可能就是全部
it is is a zero I must have those things
它是零， 我必须拥有这些东西
this is where idolatry has taken over
这就是偶像崇拜所取代的地方
now our goal here is not to rehabilitate
现在我们的目标不是恢复
people that's not what we do in biblical
那些不是我们在圣经中所做的人
counseling we are looking for an entire
咨询我们正在寻找一个完整的
inner change that starts with
内在的变化开始于
regeneration the gospel is the key here
再生福音是关键
the gospel is key not only in a person
福音不仅是一个人的 关键
coming to Christ but in a person living
来到基督，但在一个人的生活
correctly for Christ the gospel of
正确地为基督提供福音
rehabilitation says in in effect that a
康复说实际上是a
person his life can be full of strife
人生他的生活充满纷争
they can live in a dysfunctional family
他们可以生活在一个功能失调的家庭
full of depression emotional problems
充满抑郁情绪问题
and so on and the psychologize gospel
等等和心理学福音
said that's because the heart is passive
说那是因为心脏是被动的
empty wounded needy and broken you'll
空虚受伤的贫困，打破了你
hear words like that all the time
听到这样的话所有的时间
they're not biblical words so what does
他们不是圣经的话，那是什么呢
a psychotherapist ultimately do he's the
一个心理治疗师最终做到了
one who meet or she meets needs offers
满足或满足需求的人
unconditional acceptance and oftentimes
无条件接受和经常
reparent
重新设置父级
a person so as to be able to know God
一个人，以便能够认识上帝
his father so Jesus now changes Jesus
他的父亲耶稣现在改变了耶稣
now has redefined as the healer and the
现在已经重新定义为治疗者和
filler of all these things Jesus is the
所有这些东西的填充耶稣是
metre of needs for love and self-esteem
对爱和自尊的需求
Jesus is really the cosmic
耶稣真的是宇宙
psychotherapist and now once Jesus
心理治疗师，现在曾经是耶稣
really heals and fills the heart then
真的治愈并填补了心脏
the heart is still passive but now it's
心脏仍然是被动的，但现在却是
full healed satisfied its whole I feel
完全愈合满足了我的整体感觉
loved and I feel good about myself and I
爱，我感觉很好，我和我
feel happy again and I feel like I have
再次感到高兴，我觉得我有
a healthy functional lifestyle that's
一个健康的生活方式的功能这是
the gospel rehabilitation but we don't
福音康复，但我们没有
proclaim that at all the transformation
宣布在所有转型中
here is the renewing of the heart and
这是心灵的更新
mind so the battle is within and there
因此，战斗就在那里
are several passages what we're
我们是几个段落
committed to in biblical counseling is
致力于圣经辅导
the gospel of regeneration where instead
相反 ，再生的福音
of a dysfunctional family it's an
一个功能失调的家庭，这是一个
unloving sinful family that that person
那个人不爱的罪恶的家庭
has and so they struggle with depression
他们一直在与抑郁症斗争
and strife and emotional problems and
和冲突和情绪问题和
angers and fears and high self esteem
愤怒和恐惧以及高度自尊
not low self esteem that's what man sees
这种人的自尊心并不低
but God says what's underneath this is a
但上帝说这下面的是什么
different heart it's sinful calculating
不同的心， 这是有罪的计算
selfish greedy depraved and full of self
自私贪婪堕落，充满自我
love that's the heart that the Bible
爱这就是圣经的核心
describes Jesus now is different he
现在描述耶稣与他不同
provides atonement for that kind of
为这种情况提供赎罪
heart he identifies the idols the ones
他将这些偶像识别出来
the desires the cravings he calls you to
渴望他呼唤你的渴望
repentance he brings you to the foot of
忏悔他把你带到了脚下
the cross so now instead of loving self
交叉所以现在，而不是爱自己
first we love God first were at peace
首先我们爱上帝首先是和平的
our heart is guilt-free it's secure it
我们的内心是无罪的，这是安全的
loves others before the human tendency
在人类倾向之前爱别人
to love self and then our life now bears
爱自己，然后我们的生活现在承担
fruit love joy peace patience kindness
水果爱喜悦和平耐心善良
goodness faithfulness gentleness
善良的忠诚温柔
self-control
自我控制
all of these things become evident in
所有这些事情都变得明显
the fruit of our lives
我们生活的果实
that's radically different view than the
这比完全不同的看法
gospel of rehabilitation instead of a
康复的福音而非一个
passive wounded needy heart it's a
被动受伤的贫困心脏是一个
sinful calculating
有罪的计算
selfish greedy depraved heart full of
自私贪心堕落的心充满了
self-love that's different then
那种不同 的自爱
ultimately the only counseling system in
最终只有咨询系统
the world that has the right perspective
有正确观点的世界
is has an end in other words ultimate
换句话就是终极
glorification that God guarantees so we
荣耀上帝保证我们如此
have to pray daily we have to ask
每天都要祈祷我们要问
ourself self-examination questions of
我们自己的自我审查问题
the heart is critical for counseling and
心脏对于咨询和帮助至关重要
becoming christ-like what are those we
变得像基督一样，我们是什么
can see them there in your notes what
可以在你的笔记中看到它们是什么
are my goals my expectations my
我的目标是我的期望
intentions what do I become anxious over
用心做什么我变得过分忧虑
or fearful over what makes me happy what
或害怕过什么让我高兴什么
motivates me what would I like possibly
激励我什么会我想可能
more than anything else in what
不止在别的什么
situations do I respond in anger what
情绪我会愤怒地回应什么
perceived rights have been denied me
感知权利被剥夺了我
what biblical standard or principle
什么符合圣经的标准或原则
permits that thought or word or action
允许思想，言论或行动
those are all great questions eight
这些都是八大问题
questions that get at the heart then we
那些让我们感到震惊的问题
need to write down a particular less
需要写下特别少的东西
that's worshipped and thought word and
这是崇拜和思想的话语
deed and acknowledge what it is and
契约并承认它是什么和
confess it as a sin on of idolatry and
承认它作为一个罪恶的偶像崇拜和
ask God as forgiveness from God and
请求上帝宽恕上帝和
whoever is a part of the worship process
谁是崇拜过程的一部分
we study God's character in example
我们在榜样中研究上帝的品格
examine how your view of God is skewed
检查你对上帝的看法是如何倾斜的
and be ready to learn how to replace
并准备好学习如何更换
that Idol and lust and worship with
偶像和欲望与崇拜
worship of God do an in-depth study of
崇拜上帝做了深入的研究
the character and attributes of God that
上帝的品格和属性
are directly involved in this particular
直接参与这个特殊的
area of change all of these things are
变化的区域内的所有的这些东西都是
important in order for us to really
对我们来说真的很重要
change then we have three models here if
如果改变那么我们在这里有三个模型
you will of sanctification three models
你将成圣三种模式
of sanctification that broadly are
成圣的宽泛地是
endorsed by many Christians but I
得到许多基督徒的认可， 但我
believe that there's only one that's
相信只有一个
consistent with the biblical model
符合圣经模型
there's the Wesleyan model sometimes
有时是Wesleyan模型
referred to as Christian perfectionism
被称为基督徒完美主义
this is a second work of grace that sort
这是恩典的第二个工作诸如此类
of catapults the believer into a state
将信徒弹射到一个州
of sinlessness which is often called the
无罪的，通常被称为
entire sanctification sin is defined as
整个成圣罪被定义为
only that which is a willful
只有那是任性的
transcription of the known law of God
已知的上帝律法的转录
anything that we do not clearly intend
我们没有明确想要的任何事情
or do or are ignorant about is merely a
或者做或不知道仅仅是一个
mistake
错误
spiritual growth takes place after the
灵性成长发生在
second work of grace by increasing and
通过增加和增加第二个恩典的工作
good works
干得好
never forget several years ago I had a
几年前我永远不会忘记我有一个
Methodist pastor and his wife come for
卫理公会牧师和他的妻子来吧
counseling and they were having severe
咨询，他们有严重的
marital problems right during counseling
咨询期间的婚姻问题
he kind of set back folded his arms and
他有点退缩了双臂
he said I don't sin and his wife did one
他说我不犯罪，他的妻子也犯了罪
of these things he says I only make
他说我做的这些事情
mistakes but I don't sin now what is he
错误，但我现在不犯罪他是什么
talking about
谈论
what he's talking about in this
他在这里谈论的是什么
situation is something like this after
情况后，这样的事情
salvation a person looks for a second
救恩一个人寻找一秒钟
work of grace in their life and as a
在他们的生活和作为一个优雅的工作
result that second work of grace that
结果是恩典的第二个工作
catapults them to a brand new level
将它们推向一个全新的水平
where they no longer sin they may make
他们不再犯罪的地方
mistakes but they no longer sin and that
错误， 但他们不再犯罪，那
to them is sanctification I don't
对他们来说，我不是成圣
believe that's biblical at all then
相信这完全符合圣经
there's a second view and it's the Kecak
还有第二种观点，它是Kecak
view higher life or deeper life you can
观察更高的生活或更深的生活
see your explanation there in your notes
在你的笔记中看到你的解释
and a unique post salvation commitment
以及独特的拯救后承诺
that allows the believer to enter into a
允许信徒进入一个
victorious and consistent life of
胜利和一贯的生活
obedience the struggle with sin
服从与罪的斗争
continues but it is lesson significantly
继续，但它是显着的教训
by the new truth that has been
通过新的事实已
understood and accepted spiritual growth
理解并接受灵性成长
takes place after that primarily by a
之后主要由a发生
passive trust in the work of God
被动地信靠上帝的工作
appropriately represented by the slogan
由口号恰当代表
let go and let God which is a slogan
放手让上帝这是一个口号
developed actually by Charles Solomon in
由查尔斯·所罗门实际发展起来的
his counseling methodology this work
他的辅导方法这项工作
here says basically that a person once
这里基本上说是一个人一次
they're saved then they have a post
他们被保存然后他们有一个帖子
salvation commitment rededication or
救赎承诺再教育或
enlightenment and they may still sin
启蒙，他们可能仍然犯罪
afterwards but it is considerably less
事后但却相当少
of a sin and we really gotta just at
一个罪恶，我们真的得到了
that particular point let go and let God
那个特殊的点放手让上帝
God really brings about the final result
上帝真的带来了最后的结果
of our own sanctification as if we're
我们自己的成圣就好像我们一样
not a part of sanctification at all that
不是所有成圣的一部分
violates Philippians chapter 2 the third
违反腓立比书第2章第3章
I believe is the biblical view or
我相信是圣经的观点或
progressive sanctification sometimes
有时是渐进的成圣
it's called the reformed view this is a
它被称为改革后的观点，这是一个
lifelong cycle of sin repentance renewal
罪恶悔改的终身循环
growth towards Christ likeness that will
将成长为基督的样式
only be complete when we meet our Lord
只有在我们见到我们的主时才能完成
this is accomplished through the act of
这是通过行动来实现的
discipline of the believer himself we
信徒自己的纪律我们
trust that the Holy Spirit is energizing
相信圣灵是激励
his efforts in fact there's a wonderful
他的努力实际上有一个美妙的
statement that we've included there in
声明，我们已经包含在那里
your notes by the Westminster Confession
威斯敏斯特忏悔的笔记
of faith in Chapter 12 of that
对第12章的信仰
particular confession now you begin to
特别是现在表白你开始
see here then that here from a biblical
从这里看到这里的圣经
standpoint we sinned but it's like a man
我们犯了罪，但这就像一个男人
walking up a set of stairs with a yo-yo
走一套楼梯与溜溜球
the sin is when the yo-yo goes down but
罪恶就是溜溜球倒下的时候
the general trend of his life is upward
他生命的大趋势是向上的
it's getting better and better grab your
它变得越来越好抓住你的
Bible just for a moment and let's go
圣经只是片刻，让我们走吧
over to proverbs chapter 4 and verse 18
箴言第4章和第18节
good example here in the Old Testament
旧约中的好例子
we only have time to do one Old
我们只有时间做一个旧的
Testament one New Testament says
遗嘱新约圣经说
proverbs 4:18 but the path of the
箴言4:18但是道路
righteous is like the light of dawn that
义就像是黎明的曙光是
shines brighter and brighter until the
照更亮了， 直到
full day that is progressive
整天是进步的
sanctification or let's go over to
成圣或让我们去 到
second Corinthians chapter 3 and we're
哥林多后书第3章，我们是
verse we're interested in verse 18
我们对第18 节感兴趣
second Corinthians chapter 3 and verse
第二科林斯章3和节
but we all with unveiled face beholding
但是我们所有人都带着满眼的面孔看着
as in a mirror the glory of the Lord are
在镜子里，主的荣耀是
being transformed into the same image
被转化为相同的形象
from glory to glory just as from the
从荣耀到荣耀，就像从
Lord the spirit that is progressive
主进步的精神
sanctification that's what we're talking
成圣就是我们所说的
about so many people who claim to
关于那么多声称的人
believe in a biblical view nevertheless
然而，相信圣经的观点
fall practically into the heirs of the
实际上落入了继承人
other two approaches the echo both the
其他两种方法都是回声
Wesley and the Kecak view when they seem
Wesley 和Kecak看起来很像
to be waiting for some divine event that
等待一些神圣的事件
will take away the strongest poles of
将带走最强的两极
sin and eliminate their need for
犯罪并消除他们的需要
concentrated self-discipline the echo
集中自律的回声
the Wesleyan view specifically when they
卫斯理的观点特别是当他们
admit that we sin all the time but very
承认我们一直犯罪但非常
seldom confess it or ask for forgiveness
很少承认这或请求原谅
or they echo this Kazik view when
或者他们回应这个Kazik视图的时候
specifically when they let go and let
特别是当他们放手让我们
God God's Word by thinking that the
神神的话语被误以为
absorption a spiritual teaching along
吸收精神教学
without its practice will ultimately
没有它的实践将最终
change them so know what we're looking
改变它们，以便知道我们在寻找什么
for is really progressive change in the
因为是真正的进步变革
Christian life let's take our Bible
基督徒生活让我们拿走我们的圣经
let's go over to Philippians chapter 2
让我们回到腓立比书第2章
because I mentioned that earlier so we
因为我之前提到过这样我们
can use that as a text to help us see it
可以使用它作为文本来帮助我们看到它
Paul is writing to Christians remember
保罗写信给基督徒记得
here Philippians chapter 2 and he says
在这里，腓立比书第2章和他说
verse 12 so then my beloved just as you
12节，那么我的爱人就像你一样
have always obeyed not as in my presence
一直遵守我的存在
only but now much more in my absence
但在我缺席的情况下，现在更多了
work out your salvation with fear and
用恐惧和拯救你的救恩
trembling so verse 12 it's obviously us
因为第12节颤抖，显然是我们
doing the work but look at verse 13 for
做这项工作但是看第13节
it is God who is at work in you both the
这是神是谁在工作中你 俩
will and to work for his good pleasure
愿意并为他的快乐而努力
how is that possible God is at work in
这怎么可能是上帝在工作
us primarily through the ongoing effects
我们主要通过持续的影响
of the gospel in that person's life
福音在那个人的生命中
providing the motivation to change and
提供变革的动力
grow you see a person who lives their
你看到一个人生活在他们身边
life in the shadow at the foot of the
生活在阴影处的脚下
cross where there is a constant reminder
在有不断提醒的地方交叉
that Jesus hangs there for the sins that
耶稣为那些罪而挂在那里
I commit
我承诺
and I should be hanging the person who
我应该挂那个人
does that is motivated by the grace of
这是出于优雅的动机吗？
God motivated towards holiness so I like
上帝激励我走向圣洁，所以我喜欢
what Jerry Bridges says Christians
杰里布里奇斯所说的基督徒
should preach the gospel to themselves
应该把福音传给自己
every day Christians why because that
每天基督徒为什么因为那样
motivates us to greater holiness and
激励我们更加圣洁和
righteousness
义
so in conclusion there's four principles
总之， 有四个原则
essential to progress the sanctification
进步成圣至关重要
regeneration is the key in upon which
再生是其中的关键
all of sanctification and the process of
所有的成圣和过程
sanctification is built it energizes and
成圣是建立它的能量和
fuels sanctification observation that is
燃料成圣观察就是这样
observing what Christ observing the
观察基督观察到的东西
example the Apostles being association
例如使徒是联想
this is what the early Sanhedrin
这就是早期的公会
observed in the Apostles and actually
在使徒中观察并且实际上
after for in verse 13 that they had been
在第13节之后，他们曾经
with Jesus and then ultimately imitation
与耶稣然后最终模仿
imitating Christ and everything that we
模仿基督和我们所做的一切
do that's what we're talking about when
这就是我们在谈论的时候
it comes to true biblical change how do
它涉及真正的圣经改变怎么做
we change and grow the answer is through
我们改变和发展答案是通过
the gospel the Lord Jesus Christ and
主耶稣基督和福音的福音
progressive sanctification we work hard
不断成圣我们努力工作
with fear and trembling working out our
恐惧和颤抖锻炼我们的
salvation but ultimately it's God who is
救恩， 但最终是上帝是谁
at work in us primarily through the
在我们工作主要是通过
gospel of grace
恩典的福音